Contact

warren.salesforce@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/walters954 (LinkedIn) www.cloudcodeacademy.com/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Technical Training
Salesforce Development
Curriculum Development

Languages

Apex (Native or Bilingual) English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Salesforce Certified Community Cloud Consultant Certification

Salesforce Certified JavaScript Developer 1

Development Lifecycle and Deployment Architect

MuleSoft Certified Developer - Level 1 (Mule 4)

Salesforce Certified Administrator (SCA)

Honors-Awards

Salesforce MVP

Helping you learn Salesforce Development | Salesforce MVP & C3PO @ Cloud Code

Asheville, North Carolina, United States

Summary

Transformative Salesforce Mentor and Engineer with 8+ years in the Salesforce realm. Over a decade in software development has seen my journey through diverse companies, from nimble startups to prestigious consulting firms, diving deep into intricate Salesforce projects and products. I've proudly constructed a robust development team, mentoring and guiding 10 prodigious developers to their PD1 and Javascript certifications. Honored as a Salesforce MVP, I'm fiercely dedicated to nurturing the next generation of Salesforce talent. Whether you're a seasoned coder or just stepping into the Salesforce universe, I'm here to champion your growth. Let's unlock exponential growth for your business and refine software solutions that resonate.

Experience

Cloud Code Academy Chief Programmer Path Planning Officer (C3PO) May 2023 - Present (2 years 2 months)

United States

I'm a founder now, so I can make up my titles.

I oversee all aspects of the Cloud Code Salesforce development training program. This includes delivering live lessons, building out the material, and helping developers navigate their careers. I also create videos and free resources for aspiring developers and build relationships with businesses to hire developers.

Delivering engaging live lessons to help developers master Salesforce.

Building and updating comprehensive training materials.

Creating fun and informative videos and free resources.

Guiding developers through their career paths with expert advice.

Building strong relationships with businesses to connect them with skilled developers.

Salesforce Mentor
Salesforce Content Creator
April 2019 - Present (6 years 3 months)
youtube.com/Walters954 | salesforcementor.com

Creating engaging and informative video content for a Salesforce developer/admin-focused YouTube channel.

Crafting insightful and educational blog posts on Salesforce development and administration topics.

Developing comprehensive and interactive training programs for aspiring Salesforce professionals.

Blackthorn.io

2 years 3 months

Salesforce Engineer September 2022 - July 2024 (1 year 11 months) Anywhere

I write code and break stuff.

Designing and developing Salesforce solutions for complex Payment and Events AppExchange applications.

Optimizing architecture and performance of Salesforce Apex/LWC applications.

Extensive development experience in multiple programming languages.

Skilled in building Salesforce APIs and Integrations

Familiarity with development design patterns like Apex Common

FinancialForce Enterprise (fflib)

Proficient in using Git and GitHub for version control.

Knowledgeable about managing and utilizing managed packages.

Freelance Salesforce Developer May 2022 - September 2022 (5 months) Anywhere

Ohanaly, a platform for Salesforce Freelancers & Consultants Freelancer & Co-Founder
May 2022 - July 2023 (1 year 3 months)

Anywhere

Co-Founder and content creator by day. Freelance developer and architect by night.

Helping companies connect with awesome Salesforce freelancers and independent consultants.

Ad Victoriam Solutions

2 years 8 months

Development Practice Director

February 2021 - April 2022 (1 year 3 months)

Overseeing all development aspects and training initiatives company-wide.

Leading and guiding a team of Salesforce developers to deliver high-quality solutions.

Ensuring best practices and technical excellence are followed throughout the organization.

Implementing strategies for effective Salesforce development and efficient project delivery.

Development Practice Lead

June 2020 - February 2021 (9 months)

Fort Lauderdale, Florida, United States

Leading and mentoring a high-performing team of 10+ Salesforce developers.

Overseeing solution design and implementation for real-world projects.

Ensuring successful project go-lives through disciplined project management.

Leveraging expertise in Apex and Lightning Components to drive technical excellence.

Sr. Salesforce Developer

September 2019 - June 2020 (10 months)

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Expertise in Apex and Lightning Components.

Documenting solution design and implementation.

Ensuring successful project go-lives through disciplined project management.

fullOpp

Sr. Salesforce Consultant

July 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 3 months)

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Maker of Salesforce magic. You dream it up and fullOpp will deliver it.

Your Salesforce experts. Solutions design, requirement gathering, training, configuration, programmatic, Apex, Visualforce, classic, lighting, integrations, CPQ, Field Service Lighting, Pardot, and more.

Basically delivering all the Salesforce goods.

Nearpod

Salesforce Developer

November 2017 - July 2018 (9 months)

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Responsible for assisting in the customization, maintenance, development and monitoring of our

Salesforce CRM platform and other core contact center cloud-based applications.

Sheridan Healthcare

Salesforce Developer

January 2017 - November 2017 (11 months)

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Salesforce Developer analyzes, designs, develops, tests and implements new application components and maintains and optimizes already deployed Enterprise applications within Salesforce.

Ryder System, Inc.

Salesforce Developer/Administrator - Intern

August 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 5 months)

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Salesforce Development- Creating and maintaining SFDC apex, visualforce pages, triggers, objects, workflows, process builders, and other sales operations related Salesforce tasks.

AT&T

Sales Support Representative
July 2014 - August 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Updating phones and promotional displays. Performing operational tasks to maintain audit-ready status in the store. Record keeping and logistics management with stores inventory.

McDonald's Corporation

Swing Manager

March 2010 - July 2014 (4 years 5 months)

Monitoring store efficiency and maintaining customer stratification. Counting large amounts of money for stores deposit. Held a store key.

Education

Florida International University

Bachelor of Science (BS), Information Technology (2012 - 2016)

Cloud Code Academy

Salesforce Developer Kickstart, Computer Programming, Specific Applications · (July 2023 - October 2023)

South Plantation High School

High School Diploma, Computer Programming · (2009 - 2012)